[
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Joshua",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise mage.",
            "job": "I can help.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "HELP",
            "keyword2": "RIDD",
            "answer1": "The riddle!",
            "answer2": "If the eight philosophies of avatarhood combine into and are made from truth, love & courage...",
            "yesnoquestion": "More?",
            "yesanswer": "What one thing creates and is created by all truths, all love & all courage?",
            "noanswer": "Oh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 47,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Landri",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A grim shepherd",
            "job": "I am here to warn thee!",
            "heal": "I am fine, but thou must go back!",
            "keyword1": "WARN",
            "keyword2": "PERI",
            "answer1": "Ahead lies a perilous place!",
            "answer2": "Once thou enters thou may not return whence thee came!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou go on?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou art doomed!",
            "noanswer": "That is good."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 9,
        "y_pos1": 4,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A guard",
            "job": "A guard",
            "heal": "Excellent",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "TREA",
            "answer1": "We guard the castle and its treasures.",
            "answer2": "That is not your business.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you mean to steal?",
            "yesanswer": "I believe you will find that an unfruitful venture.",
            "noanswer": "Then please leave at once!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 17,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and all within.",
            "heal": "Couldn't be better!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "CAST",
            "answer1": "I guard the castle!",
            "answer2": "The castle is fair and strong!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you seek Lord British?",
            "yesanswer": "He is on the upper level in the throne room.",
            "noanswer": "He will aid you if you are in need!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 13,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and all within.",
            "heal": "Couldn't be better!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "CAST",
            "answer1": "I guard the castle!",
            "answer2": "The castle is fair and strong!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you seek Lord British?",
            "yesanswer": "He is on the upper level in the throne room.",
            "noanswer": "He will aid you if you are in need!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and all within.",
            "heal": "Couldn't be better!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "CAST",
            "answer1": "I guard the castle!",
            "answer2": "The castle is fair and strong!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you seek Lord British?",
            "yesanswer": "He is on the upper level in the throne room.",
            "noanswer": "He will aid you if you are in need!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 44,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sheila",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A solemn ranger",
            "job": "I search for the inner light.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "LIGH",
            "keyword2": "SHRI",
            "answer1": "Seek inner light in the shrines!",
            "answer2": "Runes are needed to enter shrines!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou know of mantra?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "The mantra are chants needed to focus thy thoughts while meditating."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 7,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A guard",
            "job": "A guard",
            "heal": "Excellent",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "TREA",
            "answer1": "We guard the castle and its treasures.",
            "answer2": "That is not your business.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you mean to steal?",
            "yesanswer": "I believe you will find that an unfruitful venture.",
            "noanswer": "Then please leave at once!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 7,
        "y_pos1": 11,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A guard",
            "job": "A guard",
            "heal": "Excellent",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "TREA",
            "answer1": "We guard the castle and its treasures.",
            "answer2": "That is not your business.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you mean to steal?",
            "yesanswer": "I believe you will find that an unfruitful venture.",
            "noanswer": "Then please leave at once!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 11,
        "y_pos1": 11,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A guard",
            "job": "A guard",
            "heal": "Excellent",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "TREA",
            "answer1": "We guard the castle and its treasures.",
            "answer2": "That is not your business.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you mean to steal?",
            "yesanswer": "I believe you will find that an unfruitful venture.",
            "noanswer": "Then please leave at once!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 11,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A guard",
            "job": "A guard",
            "heal": "Excellent",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "TREA",
            "answer1": "We guard the castle and its treasures.",
            "answer2": "That is not your business.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you mean to steal?",
            "yesanswer": "I believe you will find that an unfruitful venture.",
            "noanswer": "Then please leave at once!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and all within.",
            "heal": "Couldn't be better!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "CAST",
            "answer1": "I guard the castle!",
            "answer2": "The castle is fair and strong!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you seek Lord British?",
            "yesanswer": "He is on the upper level in the throne room.",
            "noanswer": "He will aid you if you are in need!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and all within.",
            "heal": "Couldn't be better!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "CAST",
            "answer1": "I guard the castle!",
            "answer2": "The castle is fair and strong!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you seek Lord British?",
            "yesanswer": "He is on the upper level in the throne room.",
            "noanswer": "He will aid you if you are in need!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 86,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 23,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Chuckles",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A bouncing jester",
            "job": "I am the royal jester",
            "heal": "Good, thanks.",
            "keyword1": "JEST",
            "keyword2": "CLUE",
            "answer1": "Welcome unto the castle Britannia!",
            "answer2": "Speak ye unto the waters of the well and ask of altars!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou an ankh?",
            "yesanswer": "Then enter in peace!",
            "noanswer": "Then why art thou here?"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 56,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 21,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Seesha",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "An injured fighter",
            "job": "I fight for my country.",
            "heal": "I have a grievous wound.",
            "keyword1": "WOUN",
            "keyword2": "COUN",
            "answer1": "Deep.",
            "answer2": "Britannia.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Fight ye for Britannia?",
            "yesanswer": "Then seek out the smith named Zircon in Minoc for he made the mystic arms, only they will save thee in the abyss!",
            "noanswer": "Hmm."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 29,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and all within.",
            "heal": "Couldn't be better!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "CAST",
            "answer1": "I guard the castle!",
            "answer2": "The castle is fair and strong!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you seek Lord British?",
            "yesanswer": "He is on the upper level in the throne room.",
            "noanswer": "He will aid you if you are in need!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 47,
        "x_pos1": 21,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Shawn",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A shepherdess both strong and beautiful.",
            "job": "I watch the water.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "WATE",
            "keyword2": "PEAC",
            "answer1": "It brings me peace.",
            "answer2": "I come from a proud city.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou proud?",
            "yesanswer": "Hmmm.",
            "noanswer": "My towne was destroyed for its pride. The ruins lie on an isle at lat-K'J\" long-L'L\"!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 2,
        "x_pos1": 21,
        "y_pos1": 8,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Water",
            "pronoun": "It",
            "look": "Water",
            "job": "I hold a secret.",
            "heal": "Fine.",
            "keyword1": "SECR",
            "keyword2": "ALTA",
            "answer1": "To what?",
            "answer2": "There are three altar rooms which connect the bottom levels of all eight dungeons!",
            "yesnoquestion": "More?",
            "yesanswer": "If the correct colors of stones are used in the altars, a key of three parts can be gained!",
            "noanswer": "Oh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 21,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 9,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 17,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and all within.",
            "heal": "Couldn't be better!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "CAST",
            "answer1": "I guard the castle!",
            "answer2": "The castle is fair and strong!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you seek Lord British?",
            "yesanswer": "He is on the upper level in the throne room.",
            "noanswer": "He will aid you if you are in need!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 13,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and all within.",
            "heal": "Couldn't be better!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "CAST",
            "answer1": "I guard the castle!",
            "answer2": "The castle is fair and strong!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you seek Lord British?",
            "yesanswer": "He is on the upper level in the throne room.",
            "noanswer": "He will aid you if you are in need!"
        }
    }
]